Guide to the Elsa Guerdrum Allen papers, 1885-1976,
Allen, Elsa Guerdrum papers, 1885-1976
- Series III. Research and Manuscripts by Elsa Allen
  - John Abbot of Georgia
    - Chapter 14 and 17; Guide to the Tabulation; and Correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Chapter 17 and Guide to the Illustrations, undated (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Footnotes and Bibliography, undated (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Research Notes and Correspondence regarding John Abbot and William Swainson, undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - "Insects: A Catalogue" by John Francillon, undated (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Table of Abbot's Firsts, undated (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Descendants of Sam Wright, undated (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Newspaper Clippings of the John Abbot Memorial Dedication, undated (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Loose research mainly regarding John Abbot, undated (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Loose handwritten notes for John Abbot of Georgia and The History of American Ornithology Before Audubon - found as is, undated (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Loose Research Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Sections from Several Manuscript Chapters, Notes and Correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Loose Manuscript Sections, Research Notes and Correspondence (1), undated (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Loose Manuscript Sections and Research Notes (2), undated (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - Sections from Several Manuscript Chapters and Research Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - John Abbot's Firsts, undated (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Articles and Copies of Legal Papers, undated (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Articles on John Abbot, October, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 53)
      "A Resume of John Abbot's 'Notes on my Life' " by Elsa Allen in The Oriole, "Some Georgia Records of John Abbot, Naturalist" by Anna Stowell Basset in The Auk, and "A Third Set of John Abbot Bird Drawings" by Elsa Allen
    - Loose Sections of Manuscript and Research Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - Knowsley Hall: Research Notes to the Birds, undated (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - List of Illustrations in "Birds of Georgia" from the collections of University of Georgia and Harvard, undated (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - Transcript of Birds of Georgia at the Tring Museum and a List of Abbot Bird Drawings at the National Museum, undated (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - John Abbot Drawings - Set 4, Volume 1 - Copy of the List of Illustrations, undated (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - Drawings and Natural History of the Birds of Georgia in America - Carbon Copy from British Museum, undated (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - Drawings and Manuscripts at Harvard University, undated (Box 15, Folder 60)
    - Notes to the Birds at Knowsley Hall, Liverpool University, undated (Box 15, Folder 61)
    - Identification of Abbot's Birds in the Berlin Museum, undated (Box 15, Folder 62)
    - Set 1 of John Abbot Bird Drawings, Manchester, UK, undated (Box 15, Folder 63)
    - Sets 2 and 3 of John Abbot's Bird Drawings, undated (Box 15, Folder 64)
    - Set 6 of John Abbots Bird Drawings, Tring Museum, Hertfordshire, UK, undated (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - Birds Set 2 - Cambridge and University of Georgia, undated (Box 15, Folder 66)
      Notebooks
    - British Museum of Natural History and New York Botanical Garden, 1953 and 1957 (Box 15, Folder 67)
    - Notes on Set 6 of John Abbot Bird Drawings at the Tring Museum, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 68)
    - John Abbot Drawings - Set 1, notes from Chetham's Library, Manchester, UK, undated (Box 15, Folder 69)
    - Part of Manuscript and Transcripts from Volume 1 and 2 of John Abbot's Birds Drawings at the British Museum at Harvard and List of Illustrations from the set of Abbot's Bird Drawings at Harvard University, undated (Box 15, Folder 70)
    - Bibliography and Copy of Set I of John Abbot's Bird Drawings in Manchester, England, undated (Box 15, Folder 71)
    - Photographs of "Notes on Birds" Set 5 by John Abbot at Knowsley Hall - University of Liverpool, undated (Box 15, Folder 72)
    - Sections of Chapters 5 and 9 and Loose Manuscript Pages, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Reports by Editorial Readers, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Drafts of Article on John Abbot for Georgia History Quarterly, "A Resume of John Abbot's 'Notes on My Life'" and Correspondence Regarding Abbot Research, 1948-1962 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Original folder marked "Escher"
    - Research and Correspondence on John Abbot Illustrations, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Application for Funding, c. 1952 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Revisions - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Research Notes on Abbot Materials in Boston and Cambridge, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
      "Notes on my Life " by John Abbot
    - Notebook and Loose Research Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Tablature of Drawings and Introduction, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Title Page, Preface and Loose Pages - Handwritten and Typed, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Sections from the Chapter on John Eatton LeConte, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Copies of Information from the Abbot Plates at the Carnegie Museum, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - John Abbot's Names of his 217 Species: Handwritten List by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Loose Pages of Research Notes and Manuscript, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Identifications of John Abbot's Sketchbook at Emory University, Sections of Several Chapters and Part of the John Abbot Memorial Lecture, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Copies of German Text Regarding John Abbot, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters - Mainly Chapter 8, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 1 and Notes on Sets of Drawings, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Tablature of Bird Drawings, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Loose Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - John Abbot's Work on Spiders, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters: Heinrich Escher and John Abbot's Insect Drawings, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - "Abbot's Friend to the North" - Richard Sparrow Redman and Notes on John Abbot's Insect Drawings, undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Loose Manuscript Pages and Outline, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Sections on Spider Drawings, Footnotes and first page of Chapter XVIII, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
      Manuscript. Includes a photograph of Dr. Augustus
    - Table of John Abbot Drawings and Frank Morton Jones "Butterfly Notes from the Abbot Drawings and Manuscripts" for the appendix, undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - "The Lesser Black Woodpecker: Abbot's Mystery Bird" by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript and Research notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript and Research Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript, Notes on Emory College Set of Abbot Drawings and old version of Bibliography, undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Sections of Chapter 2: Descriptions of Sets of Abbot Drawings and Handwritten First Draft, undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - "John Abbot: Pioneer Naturalist of Georgia" by Elsa Allen for the Georgia Historical Review and Other Pages of Manuscript, undated (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - John Abbot's Acadian Flycatcher, undated (Box 16, Folder 35)
      Photographic Materials
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters and Loose Pages, undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Section of Chapter I and X; Editor's notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Lists of John Abbot's Drawings Compiled by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript, Lists of Drawings and Notes on "Abbot's Firsts", undated (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Notes of John Abbott's Drawings of Birds in Chetham's Library, Manchester, England, undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
      Includes a few pages of manuscript material
    - LeConte's Entomological Collection Research for Chapter 8, undated (Box 16, Folder 41)
      Includes photographic material
    - Appendices, undated (Box 16, Folder 42)
      Manuscript: Includes a photo of an Abbot Historical Marked noted as inaccurate
    - Discovery of "Notes on my Life" by John Abbot, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Sample of Form for Notes and Bibliography, undated (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - American Philosophical Society: Correspondence Regarding Publication of Abbot Manuscript and Loose pages on Abbot Memorial, undated (Box 16, Folder 45)
      Includes editors feedback on the manuscript and a copy of an Abbot letter about the ownership of his slave.
    - WHCU Radio Talk, undated (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Copy of a Letter from John Eatton LeConte (1840), 1963 (Box 16, Folder 47)
      In the letter he accuses John Abbot of dishonesty
    - John Abbot Footnotes for Chapter I and Correspondence, undated (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Section of Chapter on Heinrich Escher, undated (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Loose Sections of Manuscript, Notes and Correspondence (3), undated (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Research Notes and Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters and Loose Research Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript and Correspondence, undated (Box 16, Folder 53)
      Note on folder reads "Chapter 5" but not all the materials are from that chapter
    - Loose Pages of Notes and Manuscript, undated (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Research Notes - Early Version of Manuscript, undated (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters - Dedications and Tablature, undated (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - Preface, Contents, Introduction, and Illustrations, undated (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - Notes for Table of Bird Drawings, Acknowledgements and other notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 16, Folder 59)
      Includes a tablature for the "Scientific and Common Names of the Species of Lepidoptera"
    - Copies of John Abbot's Land Grants, undated (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - Check List of the Birds of Georgia, undated (Box 16, Folder 61)
    - Pamphlets on Georgia and Related Events, undated (Box 16, Folder 62)
    - Abbot Drawings materials and John Eatton Lecanto references, undated (Box 16, Folder 63)
    - Chapter 6 - Mainly Handwritten, undated (Box 16, Folder 64)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters: Mainly 8, 9, and 10, undated (Box 16, Folder 65)
    - Photograph of a John Abbot Letter, undated (Box 16, Folder 66)
    - Chapter 1, undated (Box 16, Folder 67)
    - "John Abbot: Pioneer Naturalist of the South with Special Attention to his Ornithology", August 02, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 68)
    - Loose Manuscript Pages, undated (Box 16, Folder 69)
    - Tablature of "The Scientific and Common Names of the Species of Lepidoptera Drawn by Abbot for Boisduval and LeConte for L'Histoire et Iconographie des Lepidopteres de L'Amerique Septentrionale", undated (Box 16, Folder 70)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 16, Folder 71)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters and Research Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 72)
    - Correspondence Regarding the Study of Richard S. Redman "Abbot's Friend to the North", 1950-1967 (Box 16, Folder 73)
      Also Includes Section from Chapter on Redman in Abbot Manuscript
    - Incomplete Carbon of Chapter V and Loose Research Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 74)
    - Incomplete Carbon of Chapter V and Section on Abbot from The History of American Ornithology Before Audubon, undated (Box 16, Folder 75)
    - Photograph of First Page of the "Notes and Observations on the Drawings of the Spiders of Georgia" by John Abbot at the Museum D'Histoire Naturelle in Paris, c.1953 (Box 16, Folder 76)
      Also includes a letter in German from the Entomological Institut in Zurich
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 16, Folder 77)
    - Drafts of Footnotes, undated (Box 16, Folder 78)
    - Sections of Chapter III and V, Loose Manuscript Sections and Bibliography, undated (Box 16, Folder 79)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, Title Page and Table of Contents, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Includes Preface, Introduction, Chapter II and VII as well as loose sections of other chapters, List of Illustrations, and map of Georgia
    - Sections of Chapter IV on John Eatton LeConte, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Section of Acknowledgements and Chapter II, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Chapter XVIII - Introduction to John Abbot's Work on Birds, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Draft of Preface and Bibliographic Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Loose Manuscript Pages and Research Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Include a brief description of John Abbot "submitted to Mrs. Barrow early December 1956"
    - Talk on John Abbot for Ornithological Seminar, November 12, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Articles, notes and Correspondence, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Includes materials written by Frank Morton Jones
    - Research and Correspondence, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters and a Short History of the Project, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript and Research Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript, Research Notes and Correspondence, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Notes on Abbot Sketchbook at Emory University, c. 1937-1956 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      Notebook: Includes Correspondence in the Pages and John Bachman Review Notes
    - Small Notebook and Expense Ledger, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Notes of Sylvania, Georgia, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      Notebook: Only a 3 handwritten pages within the notebook
    - London: Ellis, Bartram, Latham, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Abbot Associates, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - John Abbot Notes, 1953 and 1957 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - John Abbot Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - David Bell notes and correspondence, 1936-1965 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Handwritten Correspondence, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - "Butterflies of Georgia" by Lucien Harris Jr., undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters - Old Carbons (copies), undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters - Old Carbons (copies), undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Pages 133-147, undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Title Page - Chapter V, undated (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Chapter VI -XII, undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Chapter XIV-XVIII, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
      Manuscript: Note reads that Chapter XIII was moved. Includes a carbon of part of Chapter XVIII
    - Appendices and Bibliography, undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Notes and Loose Pages Found with Manuscript, undated (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Photocopy of Manuscript (1) Pages 8-125, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Photocopy of Manuscript (1) Pages 126-216, undated (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Photostats of John Abbot Letters, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Photostats Re: Abbots Role in the Revolutionary War and a Map of Georgia Parishes and Counties, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Oversized photostats, undated (Folder 2)
      John Abbot and Escher materials correspondence
  - Mark Catesby
    - Research and Correspondence Regarding Mark Catesby, 1936, 1954 and undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Includes a copy of Mark Catesby's birth certificate
    - "New Light on Mark Catesby" by Elsa Allen for American Ornithological Union, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "New Light on Catesby" by Elsa Allen and Catesby Letters, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Mark Catesby Materials and Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Research Notes Regarding Mark Catesby, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Mark Catesby Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Mark Catesby Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Handwritten Manuscript on Mark Catesby, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Mark Catesby rough draft of manuscript, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Mark Catesby photostats, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - General
    - Farm Journal Articles, 1920s (Box 18, Folder 10)
      Manuscripts for "Getting Acquainted with Wild Flowers" and Birds Found Along the Coast"
    - Nature Chronicle and "Exploring for Birds: The Story of the Pioneers of American Ornithology" by Elsa Allen, 1933-1946 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Articles for the Boys and Girls Newspaper, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "Winter Birds", undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Old Manuscripts by Elsa Allen - Birds, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Old Manuscripts by Elsa Allen - Nature, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
      Includes and early manuscript on chipmunks
    - Old Manuscripts by Elsa Allen - Fiction and Non-Fiction, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
      Includes and early manuscript on chipmunks as well as manuscripts relating to women's issues
    - Early Writings in Florida, Glen a Little Boy, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "The Birds of a Florida Garden" by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Birds of Florida by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Abstract of "Olaf Rudbeck, the First Swedish Ornithologist" by Einer Lonnberg in The Ibis, April, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Olaf Rudbeck Drawings at the University of Upsala, Sweden, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Notes on Olaf Rudbeck and Handwritten draft of "Olaf Rudbeck: First Swedish Ornithologist" by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Notes Taken in New York - New York Historical Society and Trobridge Museum, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 23)
      Notebook: Vieillot, Audubon, Wilson, Peale, Latham, Bartram
    - "Notes on Thomas Brown, Baron Frederic De La Fresuaye, Sale of LeConte stuff and Alexander Wilson", c.1958 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Edward Hargitt Materials, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
      Photostats of his will
    - Cambridge, England - Edward Hargitt, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Abstract of "The American Travels of Paul Wilhelm, Duke of Wurttemberg" by Elsa Allen for the American Ornithological Union Meeting, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - "The American Travels of Paul Wilhelm, Duke of Wurttemberg" by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
      Part of the Manuscript and Correspondence
    - "Early American Bird Lore" by Elsa Allen, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 28)
      "Possibly notes for popular article which is requested"
    - Literary Treatment of Birds, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Birds in Literature - Bibliography of the Principle Works Consulted, undated (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Manuscripts File, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
      Letter regarding "Minerva's Daughters," Nicolas Denys" A Forgotten Observer of Birds", A Sixteenth Century Classification of Birds," and "The Birds of a Florida Garden" by Elsa Allen
    - History of the Audubon Movement and the American Ornithologists Union, undated (Box 18, Folder 32)
      Includes notes a six pages of manuscript
    - "For Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society - George Edwards", undated (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Anna Blackburne Notes, October 24, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Reviews of other writer's work by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - German Meetings in Salzburg, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 36)
      Also includes correspondence from Sweden 1948 and 1950
    - Stuttgart Drawings, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Notes on European Collections, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 38)
      Includes Jean Cabanis' American Adventure notes taken by Edith Babiy
    - Notes on Materials at The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, April 01, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Ornithology Related Newspaper Clippings, c. 1950-1965 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Ornithology Seminar: Dictation of Committee Reports, 1940-1941 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Rice Birds, c. 1885-1886 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - "The Origin and Evolution of Vocal Utterances", undated (Box 18, Folder 43)
      Includes Slide Prompt Notes
    - "Key to the Families of Birds of the World" by Frank Trevor (a graduate student), undated (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Copy of Pages from "A Dictionary of American Birds" by W.L. McAtee, undated (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - "The Invisible College" Origin of Royal Society, undated (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - "The Evolution and Significance of sex, dimorphism and Hybridization in Birds and Other Animals" for the Auklet, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 47)
      Humorous writing
    - "Bird Song: A World of Music" by Paul Bondesen, undated (Box 18, Folder 48)
      Danish Birds
    - Dust Jacket for "Die Illustrierten Vogel Bucher" (The Illustrated Bird Books) by Claus Nissen, undated (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - Family Tree of Birds and Bird Anatomy Booklet, undated (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - "A Sixteenth Century Classification of Birds" Lectures Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 51)
      Lecture Notes
    - List of Current Ornithological Serials, undated (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Directory of Ornithological Literature, June, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 53)
      In Norwegian
    - Lists of Periodicals, undated (Box 18, Folder 54)
      Includes a list of periodicals that would be interested In publishing a review of The American History of Ornithology Before Audubon
    - List of Books and Journals, undated (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - Old Print Shop - Portfolio Newsletter, undated (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Publication Catalogs and Book Advertisements, undated (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - Index to the Authors (other than Linnaeus) Mentioned in the Catalogue of the Works of Linnaeus, undated (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - Bibliography of Publications Related to North American Ornithology" from Coues' "Birds of the Colorado Valley", undated (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - List of Bird Illustrations in German, undated (Box 18, Folder 60)
    - "Contemporary Collectors XXXV: Henry Bradley Martin, The Ornithological Collection" by G.W. Cottrell Jr., 1963 (Box 18, Folder 66)
    - Expedition Notes: Rocky Mountains, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 67)
    - Birds of South America by J. Cassin, 1855 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Ornithology book with color illustrations
    - Empty Envelopes from Original Manuscript and Research Materials, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Contains some handwritten notes by Elsa
  - Travel
    - European Travel: Correspondence and Expenses, 1934-1936 (Box 18, Folder 61)
    - European Travel Expenses, 1948 and 1949 (Box 18, Folder 62)
      Includes map of Sweden
    - Norway and Sweden: Correspondence, maps and Brochures, 1948-1949 and 1960 (Box 18, Folder 63)
    - Travel Brochures, 1948 and undated (Box 18, Folder 64)
    - Travel Brochures and Maps of Europe, 1933-1936 (Box 18, Folder 65)
    - Travel Expenses in Europe and the United States, 1952-1954 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - European and Canadian Travel Receipts, 1957-1960 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Travel Brochures, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Travel, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Travel Literature, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - New York Street Map, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Expenses for Studies in USA, England and Europe, 1949-1965 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Loose Notes and Bibliographic Cards
    - Box of Index Cards, undated (Box 19)
    - Notes and Bibliographic Cards, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Also includes labels from Ornithology Exhibit at Cornell University
    - Loose Bibliographic Cards, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)